Kids, I'm going to tell you an incredible story.
The story of how I met your mother.
Are we being punished for something?
No.
Yeah, is this going to take a while?
Yes.
25 years ago.
Before I was dead, I had this whole other life.
It was way back in 2005.
I was 27, just starting to make it as an architect, and living in New York with Marshall, my best friend from college.
My life was good, and then Uncle Marshall went and screwed the whole thing up.
Will you marry me?
Yes.
Perfect.
And then you're engaged.
You pop the champagne.
You drink a toast.
You have sex on the kitchen floor.
Don't have sex on our kitchen floor.
Good.
Thanks for having me plan this out, Ted.
Dude, are you kidding?
It's you and Lily.
I've been there for all the big moments of you and Lily.
Night you met.
Your first date.
Other first things.
Sorry, we thought you were going to sleep.
It's physics, Marshall, if the bottom bunk moves, the top bunk moves, too.
I can.
You're getting engaged tonight.
Yeah.
What are you doing tonight?
What was I doing?
Here Uncle Marshall was taking the biggest step of his life.
And me, I'm calling up your Uncle Barney.
Hey, so you know how I've always had a thing for half Asian girls?
Well, now I've got a new favorite, Lebanese girls.
Lebanese girls are the new half Asians.
Hey, you wanted to do something tonight?
Okay, meet me at the bar in 15 minutes, and suit up!
Where's your suit?
Just once when I say suit up, I wish I'd put on a suit.
I did.
That one time.
It was a blazer.
You know, ever since college it's been Marshall and Lily and me.
Now it's going to be Marshall and Lily and me.
They'll get married, start a family.
For long, I'm that weird middle-aged bachelor, their kids call Uncle Ted.
I see what this is about.
How do you forgotten what I said to you the night we met?
Ted, I'm going to teach you how to live.
Barney, we met at the urinal.
All right.
Lesson one, lose the go-t.
It doesn't go with your suit.
I'm not wearing a suit.
Lesson two, get a suit.
It's a cool exhibit.
Lesson three, don't even think about getting married till you're 30.
30, right.
You're right.
I guess it's just, your best friend gets engaged.
You start thinking about that stuff.
I thought I was your best friend.
Ted.
Say I'm your best friend.
You're my best friend, Barney.
Good, and as your best friend, I suggest we play a little game I like to call.
Have you met Ted?
No, no, no, we're not playing.
Hi, have you met Ted?
Hi.
I'm Ted.
Yes, ma'am.
It's a very pretty name.
Thanks.
It's Lebanese.
Hey!
I'm exhausted.
He was finger painting day at school, and a five-year-old boy got to second base with me.
Wow, you're cooking?
Yes, I am.
Are you sure that's a good idea after the last time you looked really creepy without eyebrows?
I can handle this.
I think you'll find I'm full of surprises tonight.
So there's more surprises like what?
Marshall was in his second year of law school, so he was pretty good at thinking on his feet.
Look at him!
And that's all I'm gonna go.
I'm so happy from Marshall.
I really am.
I just couldn't imagine settling down right now.
So do you think you'll ever get married?
Well, maybe eventually.
Some fall day, possibly in Central Park.
Simple ceremony will write our own bowels.
Ban no DJ.
People will dance.
I'm not gonna worry about it.
Marshall, I have to get engaged.
Yeah, nothing hotter than a guy planning out his own imaginary wedding, huh?
Actually, I think it's cute.
But you're clearly drunk.
One more for the lady.
Oh, hey, look who I got.
Oh, honey, champagne.
Yeah.
No, you are too old to be scared to open a bottle of champagne.
I'm not scared.
Then open it.
Fine.
Please open it.
Sure, I'm both evil, Marshall.
There are two big questions a man has to ask in life.
One you plan out for months.
The other just slips out when your half drunk at some bar.
Will you marry me?
You want to go out sometime?
Of course you idiot!
I'm sorry.
Calls my boyfriend.
It's up Carl.
I promised Ted we wouldn't do that.
Do you know there's a popped heart on your fridge?
No, but dibs.
What is that champagne?
I want to drink a toast with my fiance.
I don't know why I was so scared of this.
It's pretty easy, right?
Why am I freaking out all of a sudden?
This is crazy.
I'm not ready to settle down.
How does Carl end a Lebanese girl?
Plans always been, don't even think about it until you're 30.
Exactly.
The guy doesn't even own a suit.
Well, as Marshall's found the love of his life, even if I was ready, which I'm not.
But if I was, it's like, OK, I'm ready.
Where is she?
And there she was.
It was like something from an old movie where the sailor sees the girl across the crowded dance floor.
Turns to his buddy and says, see that girl?
I'm going to marry her someday.
Hey, Barney.
See that girl?
Oh, yeah.
You just know she likes a dirty girl.
Go say hi.
I can't just go say hi.
I need a plan.
I'm going to wait until she goes to the bathroom and strategically place myself by my way.
Great, my wife.
Hi.
Have you met Ted?
Let me guess, Ted.
Sorry, Billy.
I'm so sorry.
Take us to the hospital.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, did you hit her?
Hit me, please.
This guy can barely even spank me in bed for fun.
He's all like, oh, honey, do that hurt, and I'm like, come on, let me have you a pansy?
Wow, complete stranger.
Come on, on, on, on, on, okay, go on.
Oh, these spankens.
And the jammers are, oh, not for real.
So what do you do?
I'm a reporter from Metro News One.
Oh.
Well, kind of a reporter.
I do those dumb little fluff pieces at the end of the news.
You know, like, um, monkey can play the ukulele.
I'm hoping to get some bigger stories, too.
Bigger, like, gorilla with an upright base.
Sorry.
You're really pretty.
Oh, your friends don't seem too happy.
Yeah, see them one in the middle just got dumped by her boyfriend so tonight.
Every guy is the enemy.
You know if it'll make your friend feel better, you could throw a drink in my face.
I don't mind.
She would love that.
And it does look fun in the movies.
Hey, you want to have dinner with me Saturday night?
Oh, I can't.
I'm going to Orlando for a week on Friday.
Some guys attempting to make the world's biggest pancake.
Yes, he's covering it.
That's going to take a week.
Yeah, he's going to eat it, too.
It's another record.
What's taken so long?
I know there's a long shot, but how about tomorrow night?
Yeah.
What the hell?
Chuck?
That was fun.
D. Wait for it?
NIDE.
It's a NIDE.
We're going out tomorrow night.
I thought we were playing laser tag tomorrow night.
Yeah, I was never going to go play laser tag.
The next night I took her out to this little bistro in Brooklyn.
Wow.
That is one badass blue French horn.
Yeah.
Sort of looks like a smurf penis.
It's on a piece of advice.
When you go on a first date, you really don't want to say smurf penis.
Girls don't ordinarily like that.
But this was no ordinary girl.
Lily?
How long have you been sitting there?
Stupid eye patch.
Mom, dad, I have found the future Mrs. Ted Mosby.
Marshall, how have I always described my perfect woman?
I'll, let's see.
She likes dogs?
I've got five dogs.
She drinks scotch?
I love a scotch that's old enough to order its own scotch.
Can quote obscure lines from Ghostbusters?
Ray, when someone asks you if you're a god, you say yes!
And I'm saving the best for last.
Do you want these?
My hate olives.
She hates olives!
Awesome!
The olive theory?
The olive theory is based on my friend's martial and Lily.
He hates olives.
She loves them.
And a weird way, that's to make some such a great couple.
Perfect balance.
You know, I've had a jar of olives just sitting in my fridge forever.
I can take him off your heads.
They're all yours.
Oh, it is on.
It is on till that break of dawn.
Wait, it's only the break of 1030.
What happened?
I got to get one of those blue French horns for over my fireplace.
It's got to be blue.
It's got to be French.
No green clarinet?
Nope.
Come on, no purple tuba.
It's a smurf penis or no dice.
There you are.
We got to jump her.
Some crazy guy on the man-hat and bridge.
Come on, you're covering it.
All right, I'll be right there.
I'm sorry.
I had a really great time tonight.
So did you kiss her?
No, the moment wasn't right.
Look, this woman could actually be my future wife.
I want our first kiss to be amazing.
Oh, Ted, that is so sweet.
So you chickened out like a little bitch.
I did not check it out.
You know what?
I don't need to take first kiss advice from some pirate who hasn't been single since the first week of college.
Anyone who single would tell you the same thing, even the dumbest single person alive.
And if you don't believe me, call him.
Hey, loser.
How's not playing, loser?
Because playing, loser tag is awesome.
I killed you, Connor.
Don't make me get your mom.
Hey, listen, I need your opinion on something.
OK, maybe at the bar in 15 minutes.
And soon up.
So these guys think I chickened out.
What do you think?
I can't believe you're still not wearing a suit.
She didn't even give me the signal.
What, is she gonna, is she gonna batterize at you in Morse code?
Ted?
It's me.
No, you just kiss her.
Not if you don't get the signal.
Did Marsal give me the signal?
No.
I didn't.
I swear.
But see, at least tonight, I get to sleep, knowing Marshall and me, never gonna happen.
You should have kissed her.
I should have kissed her.
Well, maybe in a week when she gets back from Orlando.
A week, that's like a year in hot girl time.
She'll forget all about you.
Mark my words, you will never see that one again.
There she is.
Oh, she's cute.
Hey, Carl, turn it up.
I just waited him to reconsider.
At which point the man came down off the ledge, giving this bizarre story a happy ending.
Reporting from Metro One News.
I didn't jump.
I'm gonna go kiss her.
Right now.
Dude, midnight.
As your future lawyer, I'm gonna advise you.
That's freaking crazy.
I never do anything crazy.
I'm always waiting for the moment, planning the moment.
Well, she's leaving tomorrow.
There's maybe the only moment I'm gonna get.
I gotta do with that guy.
I couldn't.
I gotta take the lead.
Okay, not a perfect metaphor, because for me, it's fallen love and get married, and for him it's death.
Actually, that is a perfect metaphor.
By the way, I can graduate you, too.
I'm doing this.
Let's go.
We're coming with you.
Barney?
All right.
But under one condition, look at you.
You're beautiful bastard.
Just suit it up.
This is totally going in my blog.
Stop the car.
Pull over right here.
I gotta do something.
Excuse me?
Pardon me?
Just say, yeah.
Enjoy coffee.
Hey?
Hey!
Go, go, go!
Everybody brings flowers.
Okay.
Mom, I'm not truth.
We're like, Ted's gonna get it on with a TV reporter.
It's just in.
Okay.
Kiss her, Ted.
Kiss her good.
Kiss the crap out of that girl.
Marshall.
Remember this night?
And you're the best man in our wedding.
And you give a speech.
You're gonna tell this story.
Why does he get to be the best man?
I'm your best friend.
As I walked up to that door, a million thoughts raced through my mind.
Unfortunately, one particular thought did not.
I've got five dogs.
I was just...
Come on up.
He's in.
So, Ranjit, you must have done it with a Lebanese girl?
OK. That's my burning limit.
I'm going to see if that Badega has a bathroom.
Actually, I'm from Bangladesh.
The women are out there.
Here's a picture of my wife.
I suppose we know what it was supposed to.
She's lovely.
So, Ted, what brings you back to Brooklyn at one in the morning in a suit?
I was just hoping to get those olives that you said I could have.
Would you like those olives with some gin and vermouth?
Are you trying to get me drunk?
We're starters.
It's a Marshall.
This olive theory based on you and Lily.
Yeah.
Yeah, hate olives.
Lily loves him.
You can't stand him.
Yeah, hate olives.
Two weeks ago, Spanish bar on 79th Street, Disha olives.
You had some, what up?
You have to swear that this does not leave this cab.
I swear.
On our first date, I ordered a Greek salad, Lily asked if she could have my olives.
I said, sure, I hate olives.
But you like olives.
Well, I was 18, OK?
I was a virgin.
Been waiting my whole life for a pretty girl to want my olives.
Marshall, I'm going to give you an early wedding presents.
Don't get married.
I think I like your olive theory.
I think I like your new French horn.
I think I like your nose.
Think I'm in love with you.
What?
Come on, man.
You said your stomach's been hurting, right?
You know what that is.
Hunger.
You're hungry for experience.
Hungry for something new.
Hungry for olives.
But you're too scared to do anything about it.
Yeah, I'm scared.
OK.
When I think I spend the rest of my life with Lily, committing forever, no other women.
Doesn't scare me at all.
I'm marrying that girl.
Lily, Lily, I like olives.
Well, make it work.
Oh.
So Orlando, you can hit this new world?
You love me?
I can't believe I said that.
Why did I say that?
Who says that?
I should just go.
Hold on, wait a minute.
Promise to these.
All of us.
Yeah.
Thanks.
I love you.
What is wrong with me?
Why are we still sitting here?
Let's go.
We can still make a glass call.
What do you say, little?
Oh, ho, ho, ho, and a bottle of rum.
Could you have a pirate?
OK, I patched Goorn.
We can't just abandon Ted.
If it doesn't go well up there, he's going to need some support.
Let's put like 20 minutes.
You think they're doing it?
You think they're doing it for the dogs?
Doggy style.
David's grilling college.
You had this golden retriever.
OK, we can go to the bar just stop talking.
Hit it, ranchy.
So when you tell this story to your friends, could you avoid the word psycho?
I prefer eccentric.
Good night.
Psycho.
Great.
How do we get to the F-train?
Oh, um, two blocks?
That way, you can take it right.
You know what?
I'm done being single.
I'm not good at it.
Look, obviously, you can't tell a woman you just met you love her.
But it sucks that you can't.
I'll tell you something, though.
If a woman, not you, just some hypothetical woman, would bear with me through all this.
I think I'd make a damn good husband because that's the stuff I'd be good at.
Stuff like, make it her laugh and be in a good father and walk in her five hypothetical dogs.
Being a good kisser.
Everyone thinks they're a good kisser.
Oh, I've got references.
Good night, Ted.
Yeah, and I'm a good hand shaker.
That's a pretty great handshake.
And that was it?
Well, I never see her again.
What?
That was the signal.
That long, lingering handshake you should have kissed her.
There's no such thing as the signal.
But yeah, that was the signal.
Signal.
Wow, Carl, thank you.
Something I gotta do.
By the way, you should have kissed her.
Carl, you guys weren't there.
I am so turned on right now.
Guys, trust me, I've seen the signal.
That was not the signal.
Yeah, Ted, why not on you anymore?
To my fiancée.
To the future.
Do one of the hell of a night?
That was not the signal.
I asked her about it years later.
And yeah, that was the signal I could have kissed her.
But that's the funny thing about destiny.
It happens whether you plan it or not.
I mean, I never thought I'd see that girl again.
But it turns out I was just too close to the puzzle to see the picture that was forming.
Because that kiss is the true story of how I met your Aunt Robin.
Aunt Robin?
I thought this was how you met Mom.
Will you relax?
I'm getting to it.
Like I said, it's a long story.